#### Contact

crwest55@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dr-catinawest-dnp-msn-rn-cv-ne-bca1083923 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Nursing Hospitals Healthcare

### Certifications

Nurse Executive Board Certified

# Dr. Catina West DNP MSN, RN,CV, NE BC

Director Of Nursing at HCA Healthcare Houston, Texas Area

## Summary

Over 25 years experience in the acute care setting. I utilize multiple leadership styles to create a healthy work environment which includes strategizing, envisioning, masterminding, creating, outlining and defining short and long term goals, detail plans, and contingencies. My goal is to put theories to work producing positive actions and ideas which can be integrated into a complex system. Most important is valuing caring and promoting human life.

Certifications: NE-BC, CVRN-BC

Specialties: EPIC. Trained in caring for patients on CVVHD, Cardiac Assist Devices (LVAD, Heart Mate, Bio-Med, IABP, and ECMO. Trained in caring for patients with neurological deficits and ICP, Aline, Swanz, and CVP drains.

Charge Nurse, Resource Nurse, Preceptor, Pain Management Liaison, Infection Control Liaison, Quality Control Chairperson and Liaison, Mentor, Certified Cardiovascular Nurse, Certified Nurse Executive, Crisis Intervention Liason, Project Red Lead Education Liason

## Experience

HCA Healthcare Director Of Nursing July 2016 - Present (3 years 11 months)

Alvin Community College Faculty August 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 1 month) Alvin, Texas

CHI St. Luke's Health House Supervisor March 2014 - July 2016 (2 years 5 months)

#### **HCA** Healthcare

Manager

November 2012 - November 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Serve as department Head of Nursing Administration. Oversee Patient Throughput Services, Administrators On Site, Nursing Staffing Office, Virtual Sitting Department, and Nursing Float Pool Services.

Harris Health System Clinical Nurse Manager September 2010 - August 2012 (2 years)

I am committed to empowering nurses through professional development by way of evidence based research to improve quality patient care and promote healing of the mind, body, and soul. Currently managing a Short Stay Observation Unit and as of October 2010 opened a Post Cardiac Procedural Unit and 2012 opened Post Transfusion beds.

CHI St. Luke's Health

16 years 10 months

Patient Flow Supervisor

February 2005 - August 2010 (5 years 7 months)

Served as the main facilitator for the in-flow and out-flow of patients at the main facility of over 700 beds including four minor emergency facilities and the other hospitals within the system such as Woodlands, Sugarland, Lakeside etc. and any outside facilities seeking specialized services at the facility. Consistently displayed compassion, helpfulness, and consideration to patients, significant others, and guests. Worked collaboratively with colleagues, other departments, and disciplines to assure patients, customers and stakeholders needs and requests were met in a timely manner measured by patient satisfaction scores as defined by the Hospital Executive Council.

#### Registered Nurse

November 1993 - August 2010 (16 years 10 months)

Worked as an acute care Post Cardiovascular Intensive Care, Medical, and Neurology RN providing bedside care, treatment and clinical documentation for patients on cardiac and medical-surgical ICU's. Served as a Quality Control Chairperson, Preceptor, Schedule Coordinator, and Pain Management Liaison to a 50 bed unit and 20 bed unit collecting data internally on all selected core measures and quality standards generating charts and control data and disbursed it to the nursing staff for improvement measures.

## Education

Walden University

Doctor of Nursing Practice - DNP, Nursing Executive, Nursing Administration, Nursing Research · (2011 - 2014)

Walden University

MSN, Master's of Science in Nursing · (2006 - 2008)

Prairie View A&M University

BSN, Science in Nursing · (1996 - 1998)